Cole B. Hamilton Senior Data Analyst, Adjunct Professor El Paso, TX

<u>Cbhami02@louisville.edu</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/hamiltoncole/</u>

Self-driven professional with excellent writing skills with mastery in higher education, managing analysts, recruitment training, and agile team building in the United States Army. Flexible and devoted professional used to a fast-paced environment where problem-solving is crucial. Well-versed in using statistical and data analysis to identify underperforming areas and manage courses to increase junior members.

Skills

- Master in Agile Project Management, Human Resources, Leadership, and Staff Development.
- Highly advanced skills in data cleaning, data visualization, and report construction.
- Experienced in synchronous and asynchronous course facilitation, content design, virtual communication, D2L Brightspace, Blackboard Learn, and M.S. Teams.
- Proficient in R, Python, SQL, M, and DAX languages.

Teaching Experience

Graduate Adjunct Faculty – Rasmussen University

Jan 2023 - Present

 Adjunct faculty member for the MBA program at Rasmussen University. Utilized Blackboard Learning Management System to facilitate graduate students as they complete Competency-Based Education courses asynchronously. Concentration areas included Value Chain and Operations Management.

Undergraduate Adjunct Faculty – Southern New Hampshire University Jul 2022 - Present

• Influential adjunct faculty member of the SNHU family. Instructed two courses per term at the undergraduate level on the D2L platform. Concentration areas included Business Administration, Business Analytics, Organizational Leadership, and Business Management.

Course Manager – U.S. Army 5th Recruiting Brigade Headquarters

Jul 2020 – Jul 2022

 Primary instructor and course manager for the Deputy Station Commander Course. Taught inperson and virtual courses throughout Blackboard Learn and Microsoft Teams. Provided synchronous and asynchronous instruction to learners. Managed a course that covered thirteen states and diverse groups of students.

Military Experience

U.S. Army Sergeants Major Academy Student - El Paso, TX

Aug 2022 - Present

• Student in Class 73 of the distinguished Sergeants Major Academy.

Senior Data Analyst - San Antonio, TX

July 2020 – Aug 2022

- Senior Data Analyst for the largest regional headquarters within the United States Army Recruiting Command. Architected and maintained data analytics models, reports, and dashboards for senior leadership and regularly briefed trends and insights.
- Enabled senior leaders to make data-driven decisions through statistical and strategic business analysis. Gathered insights from data sources and presented findings to senior leaders.
- Designed and facilitated analytical tools, primarily Power Bi, r Studio, and Microsoft Excel.
 Executed query scripts and established means for a team of 2,400 business stakeholders to utilize and enable them to enlist over 17,000 Soldiers into the U.S. Army.

- Manages millions of data points using SQL and database connections to provide data analytics to senior Army leaders; improved production efficiencies and analytical skills across 250 stations.
- Trained staff of seven operations analysts and five training professionals to transform the regional headquarters on advanced Microsoft Excel and Power Bi report development.
- Established an automated Mission Report and Mission Dashboard updated and published daily
 with code pulled from ODBC through R, SQL, M, and DAX scripting languages. Articulated
 regular benchmark achievements and performance through presentations while articulating
 insights to senior leaders.

District Recruiting Manager

May 2018 - July 2020

- Served as the Senior Enlisted Advisor facilitating one of three companies covering all enlisted
 accessions and officer commissioning in Iowa. Led a geographically dispersed team to contact,
 interview, and enlist over 400 new Soldiers into the U.S. Army.
- Upskilled over 30 senior army leaders in business solutions and business decision-making through managing annual evaluations, awards and commendations, counseling, and mentoring.
- Generated business insights through data exploration and business intelligence methods. Used data and business intelligence to train new team members and increase enlistments by 130%.

Recruiting Manager / Senior NCO – U.S. Army Recruiting Command Engineer Supervisor / Junior NCO – U.S. Army Reserve Command Engineer Paratrooper / Junior NCO – 82nd Airborne Division

Jul 2010 - May 2018 Mar 2009 - Jul 2010 Oct 2004 - May 2009

Education

Graduate Certificate in Data Science (Est Aug 2023)

University of Louisville, KY

Doctor of Philosophy, Human Resource Management (GPA 3.77)

Northcentral University, La Jolla, CA

Master of Arts, Leadership and Management (GPA 3.5)

Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA

Master of Business Administration in Finance (GPA 3.82)

• Post University, Waterbury, CT

Resources

- Complete list of certifications: https://tabsoft.co/3D2QGoV
- GitHub portfolio: https://github.com/Cbhami/Coraline

Top Certifications

PMI-PMP | SHRM-SCP | PMI-DASSM | Lean Six Sigma Master Black Belt | PL-300 MSFT Power Bi Data Analyst | CompTIA Data+, Project+, Security+, A+